

### Hello! I'm Zoe

aka Irina Valeeva

#### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a passionate designer based in Helsinki, Finland. I strive to create work that is not only visually stunning but also thoughtfully crafted to bring joy and delight to its users.

I have 3+ years experience in graphic design. Additionally, I have service design, UI and UX design skills. I'm also a creative artist, able to transform your ideas into stunning illustrations that truly capture the essence of your brand or project.

My positions showed that I'm self-motivated, problem solver and a great team player.

#### **EDUCATION**

Aalto University (2020 - ongoing) **Bachelor of Arts and Design** 

Vocational College of Piippola, Finland (2015 - 2017) Undergraduate Degree, Industrial & Product Design

#### **PORTFOLIO LINK**

behance.net/ zoeyanko

#### CONTACT

+358469544292 zoe.yanko@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ irina-valeeva

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Fluent Finnish - Puhun vähän Russian - Native

#### **HOBBIES**

PhotographySwimming

## BELOVED TOOLS & YEARS OF USING THEM

Illustrator - 4 years Photoshop - 4 years InDesign - 4 years Figma - 2 years Premiere Pro - 2 years Blender - 1 year

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Service Design Intern at City of Helsinki (May 2022 - Aug 2022)

Throughout the project, I contributed to the research, conducted in-person interviews and workshops, and took an active role in the ideation. I created visuals for the workshops and tasks for the interviewee, motion Figma prototype, presentation slides, persona illustrations, report layout, storyboards and user journey map. Our project received great feedback from the City of Helsinki teams.

#### Head of visuals at Dash

(Jan 2021 - Oct 2021)

№ I was in charge of visual materials, consistent online presence and social media marketing. The position introduced me to the startup culture, taught me time management, and working under time pressure. I've been creating presentation slides, infographics, social media content, website and printed materials design. Additionally, I took a part in the ideation of marketing campaigns to grow the interest of various participants.

#### **Graphic Designer at AlfaTV**

(Nov 2018 - Nov 2019)

For one year I have worked for AlfaTV, creating online and printed advertising materials for TV shows and other events, as well as magazine issues and company report layouts.

#### Graphic Design Intern at Oulun Mainoskeskus (Feb 2017 - May 2017)

© Creating logos, maps, banners and other materials for printing.

#### Hackathons

№ I'm always an active team player and get excited about solving challenges. Finding a solution is a big part, but also wrapping it up with visuals and selling it to the customer - is not less important! I participated in the Dash Hackathon 2020, where my team took first place in the Tikkurila challenge. In the Junction 2021, in the Marimekko challenge, we took second place. And in both cases, I have been the visual manager of the teams.

#### Freelance experience

№ I take freelance gigs to create illustrations, graphic design and animations for different clients, such as: Empire cycling - empirecycling. dk; Our Labor is Joy - ourlaborisjoy.com; Fiksuruoka - fiksuruoka.fi.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Fast learner**

If I meet a challenge that I can't solve with my current skills, I always can adapt and learn new ways or new software to meet my goal.

#### Graphic design / Illustration

I am a creative person, and can easily visualize ideas. I have an eye for aesthetics, and a great knowledge of Illustrator, Photoshop, and Indesign. I can create materials for the web and for printing, creative logos, infographics, and marketing materials.

#### **UI / UX**

I am the one to carefully develop a Figma prototype with a user-centred approach in mind. For me, it's important the comfort of the app use and accessibility. Additionally, I know how to facilitate a workshop with users to test the app's features.

#### **b** Branding

It's an exciting task - to develop a brand identity and maintain a consistent brand presence throughout media platforms.

#### Video editing

I'm good with video editing in Premier Pro. Additionally, I create animated illustrations and motion graphics in After Effects.

#### Communication and teamwork

In the past, I was lucky to collaborate with people of different ages and from various fields. In the team, I am socially orientated, dynamic and outgoing. I often take a role of "shaper", and if I see ineffectiveness, I'm ready to challenge it.

# Looking forward to working with you!